<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>I. Am. Carrico.</title>
		<description></description>
		<link>http://iamcarrico.com</link>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why is SXSW so successful?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, thousands of people come to Austin, Texas, for the annual &lt;a href=&quot;http://sxsw.com/&quot;&gt;SXSW festival&lt;/a&gt;. And each year it sets record numbers for participants and partygoers that attend. What drives droves of people from across the globe to the city for SXSW? The event is so large that there is not a single reason behind its success, but many. Here are a few I find compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anything-can-happen&quot;&gt;Anything can happen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mx7yky2C9Gk&quot;&gt;impromptu concerts by Jack White&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&quot;http://laughingsquid.com/twitter-wins-sxsw-web-award/&quot;&gt;Twitter’s launch&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fwwEGjGbxXM&quot;&gt;Bill Murray serving tequila&lt;/a&gt;— anything can happen at SXSW. My favorite encouter was a few years back, where I was able to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeldman.com/&quot;&gt;Jeffrey Zeldman’s&lt;/a&gt; impromptu “Sherpa” prior to his presentation. I have met many of my industry’s movers and shakers, as well as some of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ronenv.com/&quot;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vermin_Supreme&quot;&gt;interesting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/timoreilly&quot;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt; in the world. In short, you never know what is going to happen any day of the festival. It is just important to keep your eyes and ears open in order to be ready for what the day might bring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;austins-weather&quot;&gt;Austin’s weather&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid-March in Austin usually comes with temperate climate. Excluding a few years, the weather has been bright and warm. It is a great time to get out of the seasonably cold weather of the north to enjoy some good southern sun. Even this year, with Austin’s varying weather in March, it is looking like the week will be quite beautiful overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;amazing-content&quot;&gt;Amazing content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Hugh_W_Forrest&quot;&gt;Hugh Forrest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shawnokeefe&quot;&gt;Shawn O’Keefe&lt;/a&gt; and the rest of the SXSW Interactive team brings in some of the best speakers across the globe. With these speakers comes not just amazing content, but also sparks great conversation. SXSW inspires new and interesting ideas at every turn. I spend most of the week thinking about what the year is going to bring and what new ideas I can apply to my current project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interactive content is not even a third of what SXSW has to offer. The festival also has film, featuring amazing content by talented filmmakers from across the globe. SXSWedu has already begun and they have been sharing innovations across the world of education. Of course, the foundation of SXSW is the music. The music where huge artists, rising stars, and international groups come together and fill Austin’s streets, parks, and bars with new and inspiring sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;parties-parties-everywhere&quot;&gt;Parties, parties everywhere&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have two rules for the participants SXSW. First, do not pay for your drinks, but always tip your bartender. Second, do not wait to get into a party. During the festival are many events across the city, and there is always a place ready to meet and greet new people. Austinites love the free events that come with SXSW, and I could not agree more. Just remember to RSVP to the events you want to go to and to explore the smaller events all over the city. Some of the bests nights I have had were at holes in the wall on the east side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-adventure-on-every-corner&quot;&gt;An adventure on every corner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to all of you coming to Austin, welcome! Take in all that the city and SXSW has to offer this week. I look forward to seeing what the festival has in store, and what new innovations (and bands) come out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will be attending SXSW this year. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/user?user_id=940528772&quot; class=&quot;twitter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/iamcarrico&quot;&gt;@iamcarrico&lt;/a&gt; for updates on where I will be during the week.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<published>2014-03-06 03:00:00 -0600</published>
				<link>http://iamcarrico.com/why-is-sxsw-so-succesful</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Mobi Sites Are Over, Stop Trying</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I have moments of irrational anger toward articles I find on the internet. Today, I found one such article that was a compare and contrast to the benifits of having a mobile site vs having a responsive site. I will be the first to admit that rebuilding a site’s front end to be responsive is not an cheap task. It takes time, money, and a team willing to redesign not just the look at feel, but also document hierarchy. But that difficulty should not be feared, it should be surmounted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-i-dislike-mobile-sites&quot;&gt;Why I dislike mobile sites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search Engine Optimization: Having a non-performant site, having two different domains (or sub-domains), and duplicate content are all elements on a site that can negatively affect SEO. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/webmasters/googleforwebmasters/&quot;&gt;Google Webmaster’s guide&lt;/a&gt; for a lot more information on how SEO can be improved on a site, and what &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/webmasters/smartphone-sites/details&quot;&gt;Google recomends for mobile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User Experience: Many sites have tried to have a mobile site and a desktop site, and generally linking between the two have always hurt a user’s experience. XKCD has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/869/&quot;&gt;webcomic humourizing&lt;/a&gt; the poor linking that having a mobile redirect has. These problems are even greater if mobile navigation, content, etc are different on the two sites.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile Redirects: Most redirects rely on user agent sniffing, which is unreliable at best. There have been a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitepoint.com/why-browser-sniffing-stinks/&quot;&gt;multitude&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://farukat.es/journal/2011/02/499-lest-we-forget-or-how-i-learned-whats-so-bad-about-browser-sniffing&quot;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt; on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Browser_detection_using_the_user_agent&quot;&gt;subject&lt;/a&gt;, so I shall not beat a dead horse, but it goes against the princliples of feature detection, progressive enhancement, and graceful degradation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social sharing: Johhny is on their phone and shares a link from a site’s mobile site on Facebook. Lisa is his friend, sees the link on her desktop and looks at it. Whelp, it is the mobile site and she hates that she cannot see all the content she wants. Moreover, if  share counts are important, there are now have two different sites that are being shared, thus hurting the overall count.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Budget: The post I read had one excellent point, which is that creating a responsive site will cost more than a templated .mobi site. To create a true responsive site that is mobile-first, we must start the design process from scratch. From my experience, retrofitting a site to be responsive from a current site is far more work than it is worth. That being said, I will always be a proponent of doing the site right once, than poorly twice. If it is not in the budget this year to redesign the site, then put budget away for next year. Less money will be spent long term, and a better product will surface then if a mobile site is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;responsive-or-bust&quot;&gt;Responsive or bust&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A website is a company’s image to the world. It is important that a website puts the best foot forward. Mobile sites are dying, and their UX patterns are dying with them. The question between a mobile site or a responsive site is not the right question anymore, but instead is there the time and budget to create a responsive site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<published>2014-02-12 06:00:00 -0600</published>
				<link>http://iamcarrico.com/mobile-sites-are-over</link>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>I Am No Designer</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;There are many who would count me amongst designers, I am not one of those people. I work with desiners, I can see a good design from a bad one… but I am no designer. This is probably why after years of trying to make a fancy blog, something noteworthy, something catchy to the eye— I opted instead to bring something simple to the board. &lt;!--more--&gt; Something that would bring what a blog is most needed for, it’s content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus I present to the world, my personal blog I. Am. Carrico. A little blog of the musings of a web developer, aerialist, libertine and dubious philosopher. Build upon &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; with some lovely &lt;a href=&quot;http://gruntjs.com/&quot;&gt;grunt&lt;/a&gt; and compass magic tossed in… it is a simple, easy place for you to find my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in the tools I used to build such a place, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ChinggizKhan/grunt-poole&quot;&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt; I built from the lessons I learned here. It has a grunt template that contains a jekyll site, compass plugins and some magic with compass. It is a good starting point for anybody wanting to learn more about these awesome tools. I will write more soon about deployment and how to use grunt to make you life immesensely easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Github repo, Mr. Poole— a jekyll, grunt and compasss template. https://github.com/ChinggizKhan/grunt-poole&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<published>2013-05-13 07:00:00 -0500</published>
				<link>http://iamcarrico.com/i-am-no-designer</link>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>